Jump down!
Woohoo!
Finally, it's shower time! I stink.
Yay!
I'm scared.
Hurry up. Jump!
Get on, Dum.
Jump in. What are you afraid of?
Jump down. Jump.
Hey! Got it.
Where's my sarong?
What's the sarong?
Sarong...
What?
Where's it?
Do you want this?
Asshole! Give me my sarong back.
Give me my sarong back.
This is not a playground.
If your noise drowns out the alarm,
you won't escape in time.
Especially you, the loudest one.
Let's finish the shower,
so you can have a meal then.
Give me!
Everyone's at it so why the
hell is he scolding me alone?
You're swear again, Comrade Saeng.
They just told us not to swear.
You're gonna get it again.
"When Light Fades"
(Episode 2)
What are you doing?
Why don't you go take a shower?
It gets dark early out
here, unlike in the city.
Understood.
So strict!
Yes, I'm coming.
Hey!
Aren't you going to take
a shower, Comrade Ying?
You'll miss your meal.
I'll do it after putting my things away.
What's your name, sis?
Dad said everyone is equal here.
You can call me Comrade Bai Tong.
Sure, Comrade Bai Tong.
Comrade Bai Tong, do you
know what... a sanitary pad is?
What's a pad?
A sanitary pad is a pad used
to absorb menstrual blood.
Never mind, I'll ask Comrade Roong.
So, if you're free,
could you tell me about the world outside?
Sure, you can ask me
anything you want to know.
Yay!
Let's take a shower.
I'll tell you. Do you know Thai Daimaru?
It's a department store, it has everything.
Is it edible?
Sure. It's a blessing to
find some food in the forest.
How do I eat this?
We eat to live, not live to eat.
That hits hard, comrade.
Next.
Thanks.
Are you alright?
Comrade Meut.
Huh?
I think we should stay
away from Comrade Saeng.
Why?
Or else we'll all be in trouble too.
Good point.
So much for being a team.
Mada...
Why did you come late?
I had a little stomachache.
Go grab a plate.
It's kinda like porridge, I guess.
This is Comrade Saeng.
This is Comrade Bai Tong,
a daughter of Comrade Ploeng.
Comrade Bai Tong, can I
change the menu next time?
Eating porridge and yams is unbearable.
Sure, then eat boiled
yams and porridge tomorrow.
What's the difference?
We eat to live, not live to eat.
That line again!
Deal with it.
You'll get used to it, if you eat often.
My dear comrades.
Our goal and ideology
are not only fighting
against the government,
but we fight against injustice,
and inequality.
We also fight against poverty
that oppresses the people in the country.
To all of my beloved comrades,
I want you to learn everything
from our base as much as possible.
So all of you can become the main force...
to improve our country.
Male comrades, while you're here,
if you have any questions,
please ask Comrade Yue.
Female comrades, please ask Comrade Roong.
A topic like a romance - who loves whom.
Must be reported to the responsible comrade.
Me and Comrade Ying, we're dating.
Dating? What is this?
It means we are lovers.
Why do we have to report who loves whom?
So the leader knows,
and can help resolve any issues.
When two people are in love..
Why do we need anyone else to handle this?
Don't interrupt while
Comrade Ploeng is speaking.
I'm not, I already raised my hand first.
It's OK, go ahead and ask.
That kid is mischievous.
Does anybody know about
The Three Delays Policy?
I do.
The Three Delays Policy is delayed love,
delayed marriage, delayed childbirth.
Love causes chaos.
The Party wants everyone
to focus on their work
and devote themselves to the mission first.
He already knows.
That's it, why does he need
to tell that he has a girlfirend?
Yeah, that's right.
Good. Sit down.
Tonight please take a full rest, dismissed.
I get what The Three Delays Policy is.
But the feeling is hard to resist.
They don't forbid it,
they just want to slow things down.
Nobody can resist it forever.
They say there's no rules here,
but in the end,
there's still restrictions.
That's what happens when you
have to manage a lot of people.
Every place needs rules to control people.
I get it, but I don't accept it.
You oppose The Three Delays Policy,
as if you're in love with someone.
Are you seeing someone?
Are you?
Tell us.
No, no, no, not yet.
I wanna know who can
stir comrade Sang's heart.
Who will it be?
Anyone who makes me feel comfortable.
But now we should focus on our goal, right?
How to make our country better.
That's all.
Three of us,
we will make it happen.
Deal?
Deal.
Great.
I don't like Comrade Saeng.
He's been mouthing off since he got here.
You haven't even known him for a day.
You're already judging him?
You're protecting him, right?
It's a fact.
Do you know
that Comrade Saeng has the
same last name as that cop?
Too bad,
The student information has been kept
with Comrade Ploeng.
Otherwise, we would know right away.
So there's no need to keep wondering.
I guess not.
This guy doesn't look like a bad cop.
Dad!
I'd better go. See you at the courtyard.
Come quickly.
OK. I'll catch up with you.
Oh! Good morning, Comrade Yue.
Hello, Comrade Yue.
Wake up, Comrade Saeng!
Hmm... just a minute.
Please hurry.
Yeah!
Hello, Comrade.
Comrade Saeng.
Ahem!
Give me two secs.
So drowsy!
Stop being drowsy.
Do you want all the comrades
at the base to wait for you?
Shit! Is it the end of the
world? I just woke up late.
I hear you.
Good, Comrade Yue.
I'm coming now.
Well, comrades,
It's time to get your bodies strong.
Brace yourselves to join
a grand mission together.
Ready? Repeat after me:
Waist, shoulder, head, shoulder, waist.
After walking this far,
we still have to do this.
If we are strong, and tough,
we will have a strength
to fight the opponent.
Come on!
Ho! Hey!
How does he hear it?
Ho! Hey! Ho! Hey!
Louder! Yes!
You're standing still though, Comrade Yue.
Switch to another exercise.
Arm circles.
Remember to shout Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Change position.
Everybody.
Time to backbend.
Get in pairs.
Look.
Urgh!
Like this.
Comrade Yue.
Help Comrade Saeng adjust his posture.
Quick!
Ouch!
Argh!
The newcomer students,
they are a good force...
to improve our troop.
Make us stronger.
We have to categorize them
by their knowledge and abilities.
Comrade Gaun Hin joined a
group with Comrade Saeng.
He was a university's leader.
He has a fair amount of
knowledge in administration.
If he works with the masses,
He could become one of our key people.
Send Comrade Guan
Hin to the Political Unit.
Working with masses
can help him understand the villagers,
so he can persuade them
to join our movement.
From what I've seen in her background,
Comrade Ying studied education.
Should we send her to the Education Unit?
Comrade Ying is a calm person.
But we're short-staffed at
the Medical Unit right now.
Good.
So,
Let Comrade Ying use her medical knowledge
to persuade the masses to join us too.
What about Comrade Saeng?
He's a stubborn, hard to control.
He could cause trouble for us.
We shouldn't let him do an important task.
But if we listen to his opinion,
we could gain a new perspective on work.
A weird perspective, I guess.
Always breaking every rule.
No.
Relax, Comrade Fah.
All hits, Comrade!
The person who dares to think and question,
and knows their way around
weapons, is interesting.
If we train him some more,
he could be our new leader in the future.
Well, let's send Comrade
Saeng to the Military Unit.
He will be able to train both physically
and in communication and mission planning.
Yes, sir.
If you'll excuse me.
It has been a month since
the student crackdown,
but the domestic communist
forces are growing stronger.
Especially the students
who fled into the forests
they've become key allies.
They use a "forest
surrounding the city" strategy,
setting up bases in the country,
and stirring villagers against the state.
We can't let it go on.
Our mission is to wipe
them out as soon as possible.
Dan.
The student leaders that
you asked me to search for...
Have you heard anything?
My team member said
they're at northern region.
Just because I'm keeping
track of the situation,
it doesn't mean I
agree with those kids.
Dad, Vin and those students,
they are not criminals.
But they are on the other side.
You should be aware of
your own standpoint too.
Your aim has improved a lot.
I have a talent. It's
a piece of cake, bro.
Stop shooting, Comrades.
Comrade Ploeng.
What's going on?
There's news from the main base.
Comrade Ploeng, you can handle it.
Comrades, please continue
training. I'll take care of it.
The main base has given orders
to send all new comrades...
to recruit more of the masses.
Comrade Phu Pha, please
inform Comrade Yaguar.
Prepare to lead all new
comrades into the village.
Yes, sir.
Comrade Yue,
I want you to train Comrade Saeng
in shooting a bit more.
He is very promising.
Sure, Comrade Ploeng.
Letting a newbie
join the army...
without knowing his background.
I think it's too risky.
I've already checked.
His profile is clean.
We have the talented kid in our base,
we must use his abilities to our advantage.
In the future,
he could become a new
main force for our base.
Comrade Ying, she's quite capable.
Train her a bit more and once
she's more comfortable,
she can help ease Comrade Roong's workload.
Do you want to train Comrade Ying
to replace Comrade Roong?
Is this bad to add new talents in the base?
Don't think about who will replace whom;
that kind of thinking won't get us far.
Do you get it?
Yes, sir.
Oh, Dan.
Hello, Aunt La-or.
What are you doing here?
I was just in the area,
I thought I'd come pick you up.
I also have something to talk to.
Hey! Read it so you
know what they're up to.
Our children won't become their tools.
Rumor has it that... (Hanging with
Communists is like holding a serpent.)
They brainwash people, (Hanging with
telling them not to worship monks,
to not respect their parents.
Whoa!
They say if you find
those Red-Flag bastards,
you can shoot them before asking.
Hi, kid.
You have to be very careful of them.
Never trust a stranger.
Why don't they think that...
the students who fled to
the forest, are just innocent?
They are our children.
I might disagree with Vin,
but I believe that Vin
is not what others say.
Aunt La-or. I...
I heard that Vin might be at the base
in the northern region.
I'm going to be on duty there.
If I see him I'll definitely inform you.
Thank you so much, Dan.
Dan, I want to give him
something through you.
No problem, Aunt La-or.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Stealth movement training
means moving as quietly as possible
on the battlefield.
The moment the enemy knows our spot,
we turn from hunters into the hunted.
Wherever I hear a sound,
Ouch!
I'll shoot.
If I hear any movement from you next time,
I won't aim at your body,
but straight at the forehead.
Ouch!
Whoever reaches the big tree first
will receive a reward from me.
Whoa!
What's wrong with you?
I reached it first.
Where's my reward?
Do you have it?
A banana?
I run for a mile, just to get a banana?
That's the reward.
A reward?
Eat it. You'll gain more strength to run.
Comrade!
I've seen Thai soldiers patrolling nearby.
Take everyone back to the base.
I'll check on it.
I'll go with you.
No, you won't.
The rest of you follow me.
Go.
Why are you following me?
Go back to the base.
But...
That's an order.
You arrived later than I thought.
Oh!
How did you get here before us?
What about the Thai soldiers?
The soldiers can't intrude on our base.
Actually, another comrade
is practicing shooting.
This is just a test.
In a real situation,
whoever panics will die.
Where's Comrade Saeng?
Well...
Where is he?
You two, head to the stream we just left.
Both of you, search at the
yard where we had practiced.
I'll search along the path.
Comrade Yue!
Help me.
Arghhhhhh!!!!
Comrade Saeng!
It's me. Comrade Saeng.
Comrade Saeng.
It's me.
Comrade Yue!
Where have you been?
I've been trying to find you.
It's OK, Comrade Saeng.
If I'm here, you'll be fine.
Go back to the base.
Get on my back.
Get on your back?
This area is all Hmong villages.
Where are you going?
Gathering some forest stuff.
I see.
Good luck!
The path to the left leads up the mountain.
And the right leads to the stream.
As for this route... that side
uses it to transport supplies.
Supplies?
Shi Wang.
Ma'am.
Do you know where she lives?
Yes, I do.
Do you want me to send more rice, elder?
My family barely has
enough to eat as it is.
Whether you have it or not,
that's not my damn business!
If you don't want
trouble, then do as I say.
Please, I beg of you, Please help me!
Yaguar.. Yaguar.. Your mother fainted!
Mother! Mother!
Let's go inside first.
Mother!
Your mother fainted. Luckily,
this gentleman helped her just in time.
Thank you so much for saving my mother.
But... who are you?
I've never seen your
face around here before.
He's from Bangkok.
He's here looking for land
to grow vegetables for sale.
Thank you again.
We should head back now.
Let your mother get some rest.
If she doesn't get any better,
have Yang Sue come and tell me.
Thank you, sir. You're a truly good man.
Was there trouble earlier?
Things looked a bit tense.
It's about the rice.
This field I'm farming... it's not mine.
I have to give a portion to the landlord,
and another to the village chief.
Whatever's left is all we have to eat.
Sometimes I don't understand.
My mother and I work ourselves
to death in the rice fields.
But we only get to
eat a little bit of the rice.
That's how it is. We
have no rights, no voice.
I've heard how hard it
is for the people here.
But seeing it for
myself... it's no surprise,
why some people choose other path.
Anyway, thank you again
for helping my mother today.
Go check on her.
Go on.
Feel better?
You should wash your
face to feel refreshed.
Why did you get so scared?
While I was running in the forest,
I heard the sound of a bomb.
It brought back memories
of that day at the university.
My friend was killed by a
bomb right in front of me.
Haven't you forgotten what
happened at the university?
I feel guilty that my friend was killed,
and I still feel guilty for surviving.
You know, it's not your fault.
I get how you feel.
No one can escape the guilt.
Just keep holding on,
and speak for your friend.
Do it for him,
the things he'll never
get a chance to do.
Why do you smoke?
Do you have anything on your mind?
It's OK if you don't want
to share, I'm just asking.
I saw the people I love,
all of my comrades,
die right in front of me.
It happened everyday
until it became normal.
I don't know yet,
when it'll be my turn.
This smoke...
is like a reminder that I'm still alive.
I guess... it's just an excuse
to make yourself look cool.
Am I right?
So, am I cool?
Mm.
They live hand-to-mouth here
because they don't have money.
Most of them forage for food
in the forests and mountains.
How many families live here?
I didn't count them,
but there were probably several dozen.
Ask anything you want.
Why did you bring us on a trip today?
Who said we're on a trip?
Comrade Ploeng trusts you
to reach out to the
masses. We're here to work.
I know. Just kidding.
Our job is to invite as many
people as possible to join.
The more people you win
over, the faster you'll win.
To get someone to join us,
you must learn to give first.
Just wandering in, who's
going to join with you?
Give?
We don't even have
enough meat to eat ourselves,
so how can we give to anyone?
Give what you can. Eat just
enough, use just enough,
The rest can be
shared with others.
If you have nothing, go help them out.
It's simple. Students like
you should understand.
Hey! Help!
Help! Help my child!
Help my child!